Guide to the John Burchard papers, [ca. 1928-1995]
Burchard, John papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
John Burchard papers, [ca. 1928-1995]
6793
Burchard, John.
2.5 cubic feet.
Correspondence, printed materials, publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers related to the Telluride Association and Deep Springs College. Includes newsletters, reports, and correspondence.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
John Burchard attended Deep Springs College between 1928 - 1930. He resided at Telluride House 1931 - 1934.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers related to the Telluride Association and Deep Springs College. Includes newsletters, reports, and correspondence.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Burchard, John.; Deep Springs College -- Students.; Deep Springs College -- Alumni and alumnae.; Telluride Association.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Box 4 closed until 2038.
RELATED MATERIALS
Related collections: L.L. Nunn Papers, #37-4-1770, http://resolver.library.cornell.edu/cgi-bin/EADresolver?id=RMA01770 and Deep Springs College Records, #6428.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Associates related to Deep Springs and Telluride Association
Boxes 1, 3
Series II. Correspondence and records
Boxes 1, 3, 4
Series III. Published newsletters and reports
Box 2
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Associates related to Deep Springs and Telluride Association
    - Beaumont, John, 1993 - 1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Correspondence
    - Conable, Barber, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      "Banker to the World" from Cornell Alumni News, July 1990
    - Cronk, Ed and Dorothy (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Deep Springs brochure
    - deBeers, Jack, 1967 - 1988 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Quebec Terrace correspondence, some legal-size
    - For DeBeers, 1980 - 1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Correspondence, Quebec Terrance papers, Cornell campus photographs
    - Dodge, Norton, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Newsclippings
    - Grant, Lindsay, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Laylin, John, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Olin, Jim - Congressman, 1985 - 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Correspondence, some legal-size
    - Roberts, Dick, Helen and Roger, 1982 - 1995 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Sabine, George, 1983 - 1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Sheridan, Bob and Marite, 1983 - 1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series II. Correspondence and records
    - Fairchild, Tom, 1927 - 1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Alumni of Deep Springs and Telluride Association (ADSTA), 1974 - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Correspondence, fund drives, financial statements, reunion information
    - Alumni of Deep Springs and Telluride Association (ADSTA), 1980 - 1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Correspondence, fund drives, reunion information, oral history project report
    - Cornell, 1994 - 1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Newsletter, reunion
    - Deep Springs, 1947 - 1956 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Correspondence, two photographs,reports, typed copy of L.L. Nunn's "The Purpose"
    - Deep Springs, 1975 - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Correspondence, reports, fund drives, survey, "Giving to Deep Springs College"
    - Deep Springs, 1983 - 1988 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Correspondence,three photographs of John Burchard from 1920s included in 1988 letter from John E. Beaumont, donation reports, fund raising committee manual
    - Deep Springs, 1990 - 1993 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Correspondence, reports, literary publication The Bonepile Volume 1, 1993, fund raising, donation reports, blank survey
    - Deep Springs, 1994 - 1995 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Correspondence, reports, fund raising, alumni questionnaire, 3 pre-1945 photos including Jack Burchard, coeducation, page proof "The cattle ranch that doubles as a school for doers"Smithsonian Magazine April, 1995, "Capitol Letters","Common Cause Magazine May/June 1994 featuring Barber Conable
    - Deep springs, 1996 - 1997 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Correspondence, newspaper clippings, literary publication The Bonepile Volume Two: A Matchless Book, 1997, brochures, Campaign for Deep Springs newsletter, personal correspondence from Ruth Burchard to Deep Springs College notifying college of John Burchard's death
    - Deep Springs newspaper clippings, 1972 - 1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      Some legal-size
    - Deep Springs and Telluride Association, 1928 - 1936 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Correspondence, financial statements, pamphlet "The Debt-Deflation Theory of the Great Depressions" reprinted from Econometrica Volume 1, Number 4, October 1933, "Experimental Data and Its Use. Making Observations", "Nine elementary rules of documentation", "Instructions for Students entering Deep Springs"
    - Deep Springs and Telluride Association, 1937 - 1940 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Correspondence, reports, financial statements
    - Deep Springs and Telluride Association, 1941 - 1957 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Correspondence, fund raising, minutes, blank application forms, minutes, investment plan, constitution and bylaws of Telluride Association, finance committee, Telluride Association Alumni constitution, The George Fisher Baker non-resident lectureship in chemistry at Cornell University:"Atomic Structure of Minerals" by W.L. Bragg, Cornell University 1937
    - Deep Springs and Telluride Association, 1974 - 1978 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Correspondence, reports, fund raising, alumni events, coeducation, scholarships
    - Deep Springs and Telluride Association, 1978 - 1989 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Correspondence, Telluride House renovations brochure, fund raising, reunion events, newspaper clippings, reports, "Motivation: key to educational Problems" by Robert B. Aird reprinted from Phi Delta Kappan, September 1981, holiday photocard
    - Deep Springs and Telluride Association, 1990 - 1997 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Correspondence, fund raising, alumni events, survey
    - Deep Springs and Telluride Association, 1930 - 1952 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      Correspondence, application process, some legal-size
    - Telluride Association custodian correspondence, 1938 - 1947 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Correspondence, minutes, investments, insurance, reports
    - Telluride Association custodian correspondence, 1947 - 1954 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Correspondence, minutes, investments, finances, reports, Telluride Power Company
    - Telluride Association financial advisory committee, 1951 - 1953 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Correspondence, convention resolutions 1951
    - Deep Springs pamphlets, 1993 - 1994 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Deep Springs and Telluride Association pamphlets, 1926 - 1947 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Telluride Association and Cornell Pamphlets, 1930 - 1982 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Orville Sweeting manuscript - Chapter 1, Early Mining Ventures, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 32)
      Includes list of chapter headings
    - Orville Sweeting manuscript - Chapter 2, L.L. Nunn's Investigation of Alternating Current Electricity, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Orville Sweeting manuscript - Chapter 3, The Ames Power Plant, Built and Operated Successfully, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Orville Sweeting manuscript - Chapter 4, Founding of the Telluride Power Company in Colorado, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Orville Sweeting manuscript - Chapter 5 - Extension of Telluride Power into Utah, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Orville Sweeting manuscript - Chapter 6, Nunn's Role in the Development of Niagara Falls Power, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Orville Sweeting manuscript - Chapter 7, L.L. Nunn as Educator, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Orville Sweeting manuscript - Chapter 8, Can Business and Education Mix?, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Orville Sweeting manuscript - Chapter 9, The Telluride Educational Work is Perpetuated, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Orville Sweeting manuscript - Chapter 10, The Founding of Deep Springs, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Deep Springs and Telluride Association Correspondence, Applicants, 1928 - 1980 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Series III. Published newsletters and reports
    - Deep Springs Alumni Newsletter, 1992 - 1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Deep Springs alumni study - "Among the Few", 1980 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Deep Springs College Annual Report, 1991 - 1995 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Master Plan Deep Springs College, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Architectural planning
    - Deep Springs College Newsletter, 1971 - 1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Peace Action of the National Council for the Prevention of War newsletter, 1935 - 1940 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Telluride Newsletter, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Telluride Newsletter, 1930 - 1946 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Telluride Newsletter, 1947 - 1953 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Telluride Newsletter, 1954 - 1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Telluride Newsletter, 1969 - 1976 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Telluride Newsletter, 1977 - 1987 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Telluride Newsletter, 1987 - 1999 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Telluride Association convention minutes, 1927 - 1936 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Telluride Association convention minutes, 1943 - 1946 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Telluride Association convention minutes, 1947 - 1950 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Telluride Association convention minutes, 1938 - 1942 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Telluride Association convention minutes, 1951 - 1956 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Telluride Association convention minutes, 1958 - 1967 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Telluride Association Pre-Convention Report of the Treasurer, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Telluride Association Directory of Associates, 1955 - 1985 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Telluride Association Directory of Associates, 1973 - 1997 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Inventory of Orville Sweeting's material in Cornell archives, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      Includes 1980 correspondence with Beatirice McLeod
    - Photographs, ca. 1930s (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Telluride Association members (1935), undated Telluride Association members with separate list of names, Telluride Association members outside of CBTA